When we use three dimensional graphics for data visualization, we're going to need to
当我们在用3D图来做数据可视化的时候，我们通常需要
add photorealism in order to cue us to the three-dimensional spacial configuration
添加很多图片来帮助哦我们实现3D的效果
of shapes that are being displayed to us in a two-dimensional image.
因为这些3D形状呈现在我们眼前的是很多2D的图像
So photorealism describes visual cues that tell our perceptual system that when it
写实手法会提供一些视觉提示 以此告诉我们的视觉神经系统
see a two-dimensional image, it's seeing a depiction of a three dimensional scene.
看到一个2D图像的时候，要让我们可以想象出来一个3D的场景
Some of these cues are occlusion.
这些手法有：遮挡
Occlusion is shown here, the fact that this boys hand is in front of the frame.
这里的遮挡，让你觉得这个男孩的手是在这个画框前面的
It's start to trigger your perceptual system to think that this is
它就是在激发你的感知系统让你觉得这是
a three-dimensional scene of a boy climbing out of
一个三维的小男孩从c画框里面爬出来的场景
the frame instead of a two-dimensional image of a boy on a frame.
而不是一个二维平面的图像里 男孩在画框上
Other things like perspective, the fact that this water's receding into
其他一些手法还包括透视 比如图中的水波
the horizon and details are getting closer together in the distance.
越是接近地平线、越远的部分 画面上的波纹就排列得越紧密
Others like lighting,
其余手法还有光照
the light bouncing off the forehead of this boy or attenuation that
光线照到男孩的额头上被反射 回来，或者在传播时衰减
the water is becoming whiter as the fog is attenuating the light.
雾使得光线衰减 远处的水波变得发白
All of these add cues, so that your perceptual system that's looking at
所有这些都能给你添加了想象的提示, 这样你的的感性系统就会
a two-dimensional image can understand that.
看着这张二维图像能够理解成
It's actually a three-dimensional scene that's being depicted.
它表述的其实是三维场景
One of the strongest cues of these is occlusion.
其中最有效的手法是遮挡
For example, this red-orange rectangle is in front of this blue rectangle,
例如 这个橙红色的矩形 在蓝色的矩形前面
because you can see all of this red-orange rectangle.
因为你可以看到 完整的橙红色矩形
You can't see all of this blue rectangle,
你不能看到这个蓝色e的矩形
because it's being occluded and this sets up a depth ordering.
因为它被遮挡了, 这样形成了一个深度排序。
We don't know how much closer the red-orange rectangle is to us from
我们不知道红橙色的矩形离我们有多远
the blue rectangle, but we do know that it is closer.
虽然我们不知道红色矩形到底比蓝色矩形近了多少 但我们知道红色的比蓝色的离我们更近
An occlusion is the strongest cue and
遮挡是最强有力的手法 正因为它十分有效
it is fun to play with it with optical illusions, because of that strength.
在其中加上一些光学错觉的话 会非常有意思
Illumination helps us perceive the orientation of surfaces and
光照可以帮助我们理解 表面的朝向
there's two kinds of illuminations that we tend to use.
我们一般使用两种光照
One is diffuse illumination,
一种是漫反射
which is brightest when a surface is facing a light source.
一种是直射 即当物体的面 朝着光源时 这个面达到最亮
And we usually see this from soft objects, rough objects, things like cloth or
我们通常会从柔软, 粗糙的物体, 比如布这类的东西上面看到这一点,
pencil erasers or other surfaces that are scattering light in many directions.
橡皮表面或者其他可以把光线散射到各个方向的表面
And then there's specular illumination and that adds these white highlights and
还有一种是镜面光照明 它可以给物体加上白色的高光
we usually see these on shiny objects, metallic objects.
我们常常会在光滑的物体 比如金属上 看到这种现象
And these highlights are added in regions of the surface that are facing in
这些高光被加在物体表面 ，看上去好像我们直视这个方向看到的
a mirror reflection that would reflect the light source towards the eye.
就像一个镜面反射，光线直接反射到到观察者眼中
And so, we can combine these when we're doing data visualization.
于是，在数据可视化过程中 我们可以把两种手法融合起来
This is an example of particles that are leaving trails to show the simulation
在这个例子中 我们用 粒子运动时产生的运动轨迹来模拟
of the flow of blood in the abdominal aorta and we're using certain cues.
腹主动脉的血流, 我们现在也正是使用这样的f方法在模拟
For example, occlusion that some of these trails are in front of other trails as you
比如 遮挡 这可以让一些轨迹 出现在另一些轨迹的前面
can see this green trail is in front of the blue trail.
你可以看到 这条绿色的轨迹 在蓝色轨迹的前面
We're using lighting, because you can see that these trails are cylindrical.
我们还用了光照 可以看到这些轨迹是圆柱状的
They have a brighter side and the darker side, because of diffused sliding.
它们有亮面和暗面 因为光线照射到他们上面的时候b发生了散射
Also loosing perspectives, we see larger things here and
我们还可以看出透视手法 前方的物体比较大
smaller things more detailed at the back.
而后方的物体比较紧凑 比较小
And all of those add up to give you better sense of the shape of this aorta and
所有这些加起来给你更好的感觉, 这个主动脉的形状,
the blood flow inside of it.
血流在里面。
There's some other cues that are important.
其余一些手法也很重要 例如阴影
One is shadowing.
一个就是阴影手法。
Shadowing is an inclusion cue from a second viewpoint where that second
阴影也是一种遮挡的手法 其基于第二个视角
viewpoint is at the light source.
这个视角位于光源处
So here, I've got two two-dimensional images.
这样我就有两个二维图像了
In both cases, we can think of these due to perspective as a flat blue
由于视角差异的存在 对两个图像都可以这么认为
plain with a red-orange ball on top of it, but
一个蓝色平面上 有一个橙红色的球
we don't know if this red orange ball is hovering over the middle of the plain or
但我们不知道这个球 是悬浮在平面中心的上方
if it's laying on the plain toward the back of it.
还是被放在平面上 离我们较远的那一端
If I had a shadow, you can see on the left case here,
如果加上阴影的话 你可以看到左边那张图那样的效果
the red orange ball is laying on the blue plane towards its back.
那个橙红色的球是放置在 蓝色平面上较远的地方
But in this case, which is the exact same image I've just changed the shadow,
虽然的是用同一张图 如果我们改变一下阴影方向
we can see that this blue ball is hovering over the middle of the blue square.
我们就可以看到（右图中） 球悬浮在蓝色平面的正上方
And so in, for example, this visualization of a molecule,
再举一个例子 把一个分子可视化
you can use these shadows to get a better sense of depth due to the directions
你可以用这些阴影 更好地了解“深度”的概念
that the shadows are being cast from in understood light source direction.
这些阴影是光源从一些y已知的 b不同的方向投影过来形成d的
There's also a perspective in addition to being able to see more detail
当然 还需要提到透视 透视可以展示远处的更多细节
far away with perspective.
和透视视觉不同的
Perspective is based on size constancy.
透视是基于大小不变这个准则
That objects are the same size, but farther ones appear smaller.
两个物体尺寸一样 但较远的那个看起来比较小
You don't think that the object is changing its size.
虽然如此 你并不会觉得 物体的尺寸有变化
You understand that the visual system is looking at a larger area
你知道, 视觉系统关注的是更大范围的区域
that's further away, because of the way it gets projected onto our retina or
这个是更远的地方的东西, 因为它是被投射到我们的视网膜或
onto our image plane in the case of computer graphics.
被投射在图像平面上 也就是计算机图形学里面讲到的图形平面
In computer graphics, the way we do this is we actually make things that
在计算机图形学中, 我们之所以这样做, 也是因为实际看到的事物也是如此,
are farther away smaller and make things that are closer to us larger by
离我们远的东西看上去比较小, 离我们近的东西看上去比较大
actually moving the vertices and then projecting onto a projection plane.
事实上也是把立体的东西投影到一个平面来实现的
And so to get this perspective view where you've got the front of the table larger
所以你得到的这个透视视图里, 前面的东西看上去
than the back of the table, what we've actually done is actually made
会比后面的东西大，但是实际上却是一样大小
the primitives of the table, larger in the front and smaller at the back.
原理也是这样，前面的比较小，后面的比较大
But computer graphics does this for you automatically, so
但图形学可以自动 帮你把这些工作处理完成
you don't actually have to do this.
所以你不用亲自去做这件事
And so these examples are demonstrated in this animation from
这段动画里演示了一个
the National Center for Supercomputing Application on an F3 tornado.
国家超级计算中心 关于F3龙卷风的演示应用实例
And you can see, we're using perspective.
你可以看到 这里用到了透视
The perspective allows us to see the glyphs in the front of this visualization
透视让我们可以看到这可视图中 近处的波形
and also the patterns that these glyphs form as you go farther away.
也让我们看到远处的波纹
And so this is a storm chaser view and you can see the occlusions of these arrows, so
这是一个追风者的视图, 你可以看出这些箭头互相遮挡
you can get a sense and the arrows are larger in the front and
所以你会感觉，在前面的箭头更大
smaller in the back.
后面的更小
So you can get a sense of the depth of the simulation of this tornado and the paths
所以你可以了解这个风暴的模拟深度和 粒子的追踪路径
that these particles are tracing, and also we see shadows on the ground.
并且 我们还可以看见地面上的投影
Shadows being cast of one primitive to another and
阴影从一个图元投射到另一个图元上
also the lighting that these primitives are illuminated on one side
并且将这些图元的一侧照亮的光线
better than they're illuminated or more brightly than on another side
比他们（全部）被照亮要好 （或者说）比其他侧面被照亮
to give you a sense that the shape of these arrows are cylindrical.
更让你感觉这些箭头的形状是椭圆形的
Also, as the storm chaser moves through the dataset,
除此以外 随着镜头穿越整个数据集
things in the front are moving by the viewer faster than things in the back.
近处的物体移动得比远处更快
That's another 3D cue called motion parallax.
这是另一个3D视觉效果 即运动视差
And finally, there's stereo.
最后，这个是立体视觉
We can use stereo in the absence of other cues.
我们可以在不能用其他手法的情况下使用立体影像
In this case, I was just plotting points of a mathematical equation to create
在这个例子里，我只是根据数学方程式 绘制点来作图
some shapes and the way you visualize this is you hold your fingers up
要体验该可视化的例子 你可举起一根手指
in front of your two eyes and right across your eyes.
放在两眼之间 试着让两只眼的视线交叉
So that your right eye is looking at the left image and
这样你的右眼看着左边的图
your left eye is looking at the right image, basically by focusing on the finger
左眼看着右边的图
until those two images in the background start to merge together.
双眼一直盯着看，直到k左右眼看到的背景中的两幅图融合到一起
If you do that, then you get a stereogram and this two-dimensional set of points on
如果你这么做 就能看到一幅立体图像
this image plane should pop-out into a three-dimensional configuration.
这些二维平面中的点会凸出来 形成三维的物体
If you want to simulate this, then you can simulate this with two separate views.
要想模拟这种效果的话 可以模拟两个不同的视角
A view from a left eye and a view from a right eye,
一个视角是从左眼看到的，另一个视角是从右眼看到的
looking in parallel at the data.
这样额平行视角下看到的数据
Just make sure you don't rotate those views.
要保证你的视角不会旋转
You want to make sure the views are in parallel.
而且这两个视角是平行的
So, what did we learn?
那么我们学到了什么呢 ?
We learned that occlusion is the strongest of all the depth cues and
首先 遮挡是最强有力的 深度维度表现手法
that shadowing is an occlusion from a viewpoint at the light source.
而阴影则是一种以光源为视点的 特殊的遮挡表现方法
Illumination is useful for
光照有助于
surface orientation that helps reveal details and perspective gives us
借助一个平面的方向，给我们呈现更多的细节和视角,
different scales of visualization in addition to adding depth perception.
不同规模的可视化除了给我们提供了感知深度这种感觉。
And when none of these cues are available to us,
当这些手法都无法使用的时候
sometimes some of the other cues can be used.
有时也可以用一些其他手段
For example, stereo.
例如, 立体影像。
We can use stereo in the absence of other cues.
我们可以在不能用其他手法的情况下使用立体影像
In this case, I was just plotting points of a mathematical equation to create some
在本例中 我按照一个 数学方程画了一些点
shapes.
来构成了一些形状
And the way you visualize this is you hold your finger up in front of your two eyes
观察这些图形的方法是 举起一根手指
and try to close your eyes, so that your right eye is looking at the left image and
试着闭上你的眼睛, 让你的右眼看左边的图像,
your left eye is looking at the right image.
左眼看着右边的图
Basically, by focusing on the finger until those to images in the background start to
基本上, 通过专注于手指, 直到那些在背景中的图像开始
merge together.
慢慢融合在一起
If you do that, then you get a stereogram and this two-dimensional set of points on
如果你这么做 就能看到一幅立体图像
this image plane should pop-out into a three-dimensional configuration.
这些二维平面中的点会凸出来 形成三维的物体
If you want to simulate this, then you can simulate this with two separate views.
要想模拟这种效果的话 可以模拟两个不同的视角
A view from a left eye and a view from a right eye looking in parallel at the data.
从左眼看到的图像和从右眼看图像形成这种平行视角。
Just make sure you don't rotate those views.
要保证你的视角不会旋转
You want to make sure the views are in parallel.
而且这两个视角是平行的
We learn that occlusion is the strongest of these depth cues and
我们知道，遮挡是最好的体现深度的方法
we learned that shadows are just occlusion from a light source.
我们也s知道，阴影只是光源被遮挡之后形成的。
We also learned that illumination cues us to the orientation of surfaces and
我们还知道，光照暗示s着光照射过来的方向和物体的平面信息
we also learned that perspective,
我们也知道视角
allows us to visualize multiple scales in the same image.
r让我们可以从同一张图中看到多种规模的事物
[MUSIC]
音乐]